gonoodle.com 2019-06-04

# Privacy Policy – GoNoodle

Last updated: May 15, 2018

Welcome to GoNoodle, a website available at [www.gonoodle.com](http://www.gonoodle.com/) (the Site), and a mobile and set-top box applications (“Application”) (collectively, the “Services”). The Services are owned and operated by GoNoodle, Inc. (“GoNoodle”, “we”, “us” or “our”).

We created GoNoodle to get kids moving throughout the day at school and home. GoNoodle’s activities are available to teachers for use in the classroom and to kids outside the classroom. Your privacy and the privacy of children who use GoNoodle are important to us, and we created this Privacy Policy to inform you of the information we collect when you use the Services, how we use it, and how we share it with others. GoNoodle is committed to protecting your privacy, and has developed its privacy practices to align with applicable laws, including the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) and the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA).

GoNoodle is hosted and operated in the United States. If you use the Services from outside the United States, please be aware that the information you provide to us is transmitted to, processed and stored in the United States, and by using the Services you agree to this. Data will be protected subject to this Privacy Policy and applicable privacy laws in the United States and in the EU. These laws may be different from the privacy laws in your country. However, this does not change our commitments to safeguard your privacy, and we will comply with all applicable laws relating to the cross-border transfer of your personal information.

## INFORMATION WE COLLECT

### Information provided by users:

#### Educators:

When an educator registers, we collect first name, last name, email address, zip/postal code, password, and school name and address. We also collect your date of birth to verify your registration status, however we discard it once registration is complete.

Once an educator creates an account, they enter a class name, grade, and number of students in the class. Educators may also upload content, including YouTube videos and custom questions into their account.

#### Premium Services for Educators:

Educators who choose to upgrade to the premium version of GoNoodle will also be asked to provide their billing information, which we use to complete the purchase.

#### Families:

To create a family account, the parent or legal guardian registers by providing an email address, password, and zip code.

Children may register for GoNoodle. When a child registers with our Services, we ask for a parent’s email address. The parent will receive an email notifying them that their Child would like to register with GoNoodle and ask them to complete the account registration. If the parent proceeds, they will be asked to create a password for the account, provide a zip code, and accept the terms of services.

If the parent does not complete registration for their Child and consent to the child’s use of the service within 7 days of this notice (and we may send a reminder in that 7 day window), GoNoodle will delete all contact information from its records. During this 7 day period, the Child may view limited content on GoNoodle in an anonymous state without parental consent but after 7 days the temporary account will cease to function.

Through their account, parents may manage the Child’s account settings and deactivate the account completely.

#### Store:

When users make a purchase through the GoNoodle store, we collect a first and last name, email address, shipping address, billing address and credit card information, which we use in order to fulfill the purchase.

#### Communications:

Educators and parents have the option to provide an email address in order to sign up to receive email communications from GoNoodle about our products and services. Parents may also receive communications about their family’s use of GoNoodle. Users may opt out of these communications at any time via the “Opt Out Policy” as described below.

In addition, when users provide us with feedback through the “contact us” or other customer support forums, we will collect that information to respond to their concern.

#### Information we automatically collect from all users:

Like many website owners and operators, we use automated data collection tools such as Cookies and Web Beacons to collect certain information.

A cookie is a small data file sent from a website or application and stored on your computer or device. Cookies allow us to recognize your browser when you return to our Services and to remember your login information. Cookies also allow us to serve certain features, to better understand how you interact with our Services, and to review aggregated usage. You can set your browser to detect some cookies, stop accepting cookies or prompt you before accepting cookies. Refer to your browser instructions or help screen to learn more about these functions. Please note, however, that if you don’t accept Cookies you may not be able to access all portions or features of our Service.

Web Beacons are tiny graphics with a unique identifier that may be included on our Services for several purposes, including to deliver or communicate with Cookies, to track and measure the performance of our Services, and to monitor how many visitors view our Services. Unlike Cookies, which are stored on the device, Web Beacons are typcially embedded invisibly on web pages or in an e-mail.

By using our Services, you agree to our use of these tracking technologies.

Log Data refers to certain information about how a user (including both Account holders and non-Account holders) uses our Services. Log Data may include information such as a user’s Internet Protocol address, browser type, operating system, the pages or features of our Services to which a User browsed and the time spent on those pages or features, search terms, the links on our Services that a user clicked on, and other statistics. We use Log Data to administer the Services and we analyze (and may engage third parties to analyze) Log Data to improve, customize, and enhance our Services or tailor our Services to our user’s needs.

You may be given the option to receive push notifications while using our Services. In order to serve push notifications, GoNoodle may need to collect your IP address and a persistent identifier from your device. You can turn off push notifications in your device settings.

We collect certain information that your mobile device, laptop, or other device sends when you use our Services, like a device identifier, user settings, and the operating system of your device, as well as information about your use of our Services.

#### A Note About Third Party Tracking and Our Website

We do not serve targeted advertising; however, when you use the Internet, unaffiliated parties such as ad networks, web analytics companies and social networking platforms may collect information about your online activities over time and across our and other websites. This information may be used to provide advertisements for products and services that may interest you, and those companies may use cookies, clear GIFs and other tracking technologies. GoNoodle does not track your activity across different websites or online services. We do not honor “do not track” signals transmitted by web browsers. We encourage you to visit the following links if you would like to opt out of certain tracking conducted by unaffiliated third parties.

For more information about third-party advertisers and how to prevent them from using your information, visit the NAI’s consumer website at http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices or http://www.aboutads.info/choices/. If you do want to opt out using these tools, you need to opt out separately for each of your devices and for each web browser (such as Internet Explorer, Firefox or Safari) that you use on each device.

## HOW WE USE THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT

Protecting the personal information of our users is an important part of our business. We do not sell or rent user information to anyone. Our primary goal in collecting information is to provide and improve our Services, to administer your use of GoNoodle, and to enably you to enjoy and easily navigate our Services. We will use your personal information to:

  * Provide Services, communicate with you, and provide user support.
  * Customize your experience.
  * Measure and improve our services.
  * Send you relevant emails and communications that may be of interest to you (with the ability to opt out of such communication). For example, we may communicate with parents about their children’s use of GoNoodle, to let them know about updates to the Services, or to notify them of offers related to GoNoodle that may be of interest.
  * Enforce our agreements, terms, conditions, and policies.
  * To get the consent of the parent when Children initiate account creation.

#### Information Shared with Third Parties

We will not share any personal information that we have collected from or regarding you except as described below:

#### Information Shared with Our Services Providers

We may engage third-party services providers that help us administer and provide the Services (for example, a web hosting company whose services we use to host our platform). These third-party services providers have access to your Personal Information only for the purpose of performing services on our behalf. A complete list of services providers that may have access to users’ Personal Information can be found at [www.gonoodle.com/third-party-operators](http://www.gonoodle.com/third-party-operators).

Please keep in mind that, to the extent a third-party service provider needs to access your information in order to perform services to us, we share your information with that provider. We require that any third-party service providers limit their use of your information solely to providing services to us and that they maintain the confidentiality, security, and integrity of your information and not make unauthorized use or disclosure of the information.

#### Aggregated Information Shared with Other Third Parties

We may share anonymized or aggregated data we collect from the use of the Services, such as de-identified demographic information, de-identified location information, information about the computer or device from which you access the Services, market trends, and other analysis that we create based on the information we receive from you and other users.

We may share aggregated, deidentified information with our sponsors to let them know how many users viewed and interacted with their materials. This information does not identify any individual or educational institution. We may also provide aggregate information about teacher use of GoNoodle to their education institution administrator.

#### Google Analytics

GoNoodle uses a tool called “Google Analytics” to collect information about users of the GoNoodle. Google Analytics collects information such as how often users visit our website site, what pages they visit when they do so, and what other sites they used prior to coming to our website. We use the information we get from Google Analytics to analyze performance on GoNoodle, improve our services, including to help customize our website for users. Google Analytics places cookies on your computer, to help us analyze how users use GoNoodle. The information generated by the cookie about your use of GoNoodle (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the Services, compiling reports on website activity for us. By using this Site, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above. Google’s ability to use and share information collected by Google Analytics about your visits to this site is restricted by the Google Analytics Terms of Use and the Google Privacy Policy. You can prevent Google Analytics from collecting information about you and recognizing you on return visits to our website by disabling cookies on your browser.

We use and disclose your personal information only for the purposes described above and for the following:

  * To investigate a suspected violation of our Terms of Service, suspected fraud or other unlawful activity;
  * As may be required by law or by a court order, in which case we shall attempt to notify you and work with you to seek to limit the scope of the required disclosure;
  * To our third party service providers to allow them to provide features on our behalf;
  * In the event of a reorganization, merger, sale, bankruptcy or other business change, in which case your information will remain subject to the terms of this Privacy Policy; and
  * With your consent and as permissible under applicable laws and regulations.

## HOW CAN USERS ACCESS, UPDATE, OR DELETE PERSONAL INFORMATION?

You can request to review, correct, update or have deleted your (or your child’s) personally identifiable information from our database by writing to us at [privacy@gonoodle.com](mailto:privacy@gonoodle.com) or Privacy Request, GoNoodle, Inc., 209 10th Avenue South, Suite 350, Nashville, TN 37203. Please include your name, email address and a telephone number where we can reach you. To protect you and/or your child’s privacy and security, we will take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting you access to the personal information that we collect and maintain about you and/or your child.

## SECURITY:

We are committed to protecting the security, integrity and confidentiality of the data through the use of physical and technical safeguards. GoNoodle stores data in secure cloud-based environments and usesserver authentication and industry-standard firewalls in an effort to prevent interference or access from outside intruders. We also require unique account identifiers, user names, and passwords that must be entered each time users access the Application, or use of secure password credentials to an authorized third party portal. The Internet, however, is not perfectly secure and we are not responsible for security breaches not reasonably within our control.

We require that users maintain the confidentiality of their user names and passwords. If you become aware of any unauthorized use of an account, loss of your or your child’s or student’s account credentials or suspect a security breach, notify us immediately at [privacy@gonoodle.com](mailto:privacy@gonoodle.com).

### DATA RETENTION:

We retain data for as long as an account is active. Within 1 year of inactivity, we may delete the user account. However, at any time, users may request deletion of their accounts, and parents may request deletion of their children’s accounts by emailing [support@gonoodle.com](mailto:support@gonoodle.com).

When you delete your account or your child’s account, it cannot be recovered.

Please note that we do retain non-personal information, including aggregated, de-identified data for the purposes described in the section titled, “How We Use the Information We Collect.”

## OPT-OUT POLICY:

We do not send marketing messaging to children, and we do not rent or sell user information to third parties for marketing purposes.

We do send emails to parents and teachers with information about our Services that we believe may be of interest. Users may opt out of receiving email messages by contacting us at [support@gonoodle.com](mailto:support@gonoodle.com) or by clicking on the “unsubscribe” link found at the bottom of every email that we send.

## CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY

We may make changes to this privacy policy from time to time, and you should review it periodically so that you are updated on any changes. Changes are effective once posted on the Site. If we make any material changes to our collection, use or sharing of personal information of children under 13, we will notify parents and teachers using the email address provided during registration.

## CONTACT US

If you have any questions or comments about our Privacy Policy, please contact us at:  
 **By email:** [privacy@gonoodle.com](mailto:privacy@gonoodle.com)  
 **By telephone:** 800-514-1362  
 **By regular mail:**  
Privacy Request  
GoNoodle, Inc.  
209 10th Avenue South  
Suite 350  
Nashville, TN 37203

Please be assured that any personal information that you provide in communications to us will not be used to send you promotional materials, unless you so request.
